A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writing Project Files, circa 1876; 1953-2016; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 17 Linear feet Boxes 7-21, 30-31, 33-34, OVs 36-37; 3.72 Gigabytes ER012-ER102
  - Files on Artists, 1968-2016; 4.5; Archival Resource Key
    - Stettheimer, Florine, 1987; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Steven Watson and Virgil Thomson discussion on Stettheimer
    - Taylor-Woods, Sam, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Taylor-Woods, Sam, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER087)
    - Vernet, Horace, 1986-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Warburg, Aby, 2006; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER054. (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Watteau, Jean-Antoine, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Yanagi, Miwa, 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Zucker, Barbara, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Other Writing Projects, 1953-2016; 4.6; Archival Resource Key
    The projects in this subseries include material for books, book blurbs, magazine columns, graduation addresses, art and book reviews, and translations from French to English by Nochlin. Also included is general research material that is not associated with specific projects.
    - Address, Brooklyn Ethical Culture School 35th Anniversary, circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Article, "Offbeat and Naked" Draft for Artnet, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER089)
    - Book Chapters on Modern Art (1 of 2), circa 1967-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 19)
      Chapters were written for an unpublished textbook.
    - Book Chapters on Modern Art (2 of 2), circa 1967-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Book, The Jew in Text - Correspondence, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Book, The Jew in Text - Introduction Manuscripts, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Book, The Jew in Text - Preliminary Material, 1991-1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER088)
    - Book, The Jew in Text - Research Material, 1984-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Book, The Jew in Text - Research Material, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Book, Misère: The Visual Representation of Misery in the 19th Century - Research, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Book, Misère: The Visual Representation of Misery in the 19th Century Introduction, 2013-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Book, Representing Women - Drafts and French Translations, circa 1990-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Book, Representing Women - Proofs, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Book Blurb for Carol Zemel's Book on Van Gogh, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Book Blurb for Bachelors by Rosalind Krauss, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Catalog Entries for Classical Myth in Western Art Exhibition, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Columns for House and Garden Magazine, circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Columns for House and Garden Magazine, "Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney's Studio House in Westburg", 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Columns for Vogue Magazine, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Graduation Address, "The Role of the Arts and Design in a Multicultural Society" at Parsons School of Design, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Graduation Address, "The Independent Art College in a Multicultural Society" at Massachusetts College of Art, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Graduation Address, "The Independent Art College in a Multicultural Society" at Massachusetts College of Art - Fragment, 1991; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER090)
    - In Memoriam for Craig Hugh Smyth, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Digital Writing Project Files, circa 1981-circa 1985; Archival Resource Key; 0.004 Gigabytes 11 computer files (Folder ER091)
    - Letter to the Editor of Art Bulletin Regarding Degas, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Op Ed Letter Regarding Sensation Exhibition at Brooklyn Museum, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Research on Black Male: Representations of Masculinity in Contemporary American Art Exhibition, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Research on Cézanne, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Research on "Cindy Sherman" by Rosalind Krauss, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Research on Delacroix, 1963-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Research on Delacroix, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Research on Delacroix, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - Research on Greek Sculpture, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Research, Notecards, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 30)
      See set 7
    - Research on Orientalism, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Research on Orientalism, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Research on the Painting Le Rêve du Bonheur, circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Research Relating to India, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Research on Victorian Art, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Research on Victorian Art, Conference Material, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Research on Victorian Art, List of Victorian Poverty Painters, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Research on Victorian Art, "Victorian Painters" Draft by Julian Treuherz, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Research on Walking, 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER092)
    - Response at The Feminist Future Symposium at Museum of Modern Art, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Review of Ambition and Love in Modern American Art by Jonathan Weinberg, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Review of Ambition and Love in Modern American Art by Jonathan Weinberg, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER093)
    - Review of American Visions: The Epic History of Art in America by Robert Hughes, Drafts, 1997; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER094)
    - Review of Bonjour Tristesse by Françoise Sagan, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Review of Cézanne Exhibition at Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Review of Dora Maar With and Without Picasso: A Biography by Mary Ann Caws, Draft, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER095)
    - Review of Edvard Munch Exhibition at Guggenheim Museum, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Review of Jenny Saville Paintings, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Review of Jenny Saville Paintings, Drafts, 1999-2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER096)
    - Review of Landscape and Memory by Simon Schama, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Review of Lucian Freud: Recent Work Exhibition at Metropolitan Museum of Art, Draft, 1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER097)
    - Review of Mary Cassatt: Painter of Modern Women by Griselda Pollock, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Reviews of Mary Cassatt: Painter of Modern Women and Mary Cassatt: Modern Woman, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER098)
    - Review of Mirroring Evil: Nazi Imagery/Recent Art Exhibition, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Review of Mirroring Evil: Nazi Imagery/Recent Art Exhibition, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER099)
    - Review of Modern Art: 19th and 20th Centuries: Selected Papers by Meyer Shapiro, 1979-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Review of Musée d'Orsay, 1986-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Review of Museum of Modern Art Reopening, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER100)
    - Review of Museum of Modern Art Reopening, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Review of Museum of Modern Art Reopening, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Review of The New Painting: Impressionism 1874-1886 Exhibition, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Review of Painters and Public Life in Eighteenth-Century Paris by Tom Crow, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Review of Posséder et Détruire Exhibition at Louvre Museum, Annotated Exhibition Catalog, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Review of Posséder et Détruire Exhibition at Louvre Museum, Manuscripts, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Review of La Révolution Française Exhibition, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Review of La Révolution Française Exhibition, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Review of La Révolution Française Exhibition, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER101)
    - Review of Secret Lives in Art by Jill Johnston, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Review of Symptoms of Culture by Marjorie Garber, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Reviews of Writings About Mary Cassatt, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER098)
    - Translations of Degas Sonnets by Nochlin, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Digital Notes and Fragments, 1991-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 31 computer files (Folder ER102)
- Professional Files, 1957-2012; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 22-23; 0.001 Gigabytes ER103
  Files in this series contain material regarding Nochlin's professional activities as an advisor, on committees, with grants and fellowships, and presentations including one in born-digital form. Other files are for photograph requests, travel arrangements, and travel expenses. Conference and symposium material includes correspondence, informational documents for participants, logistical arrangements, and 11 audiovisual recordings documenting presentations during conference/symposium sessions.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by activity, then arranged chronologically within the folders.
  - Advisor, Rachel of the Comedie Francaise Film by Judith Wechsler and Rachel Brownstein, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Advisor, The Realists Documentary, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Board, The French Revolution and Political Caricature Exhibition, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council, New York Public Library Humanities Advisory Council, 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Committee, Winter Olympics Games National Fine Arts Committee, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Conference, American Council of Learned Societies, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Bellagio Conference on Study of Culture, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Berkshire Conference on the History of Women, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Conference, College Art Association in Boston, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Conference, College Art Association in New York City, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Conference, College Art Association in Toronto, 1998; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Conference, Council of American Jewish Museums, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Conference, Edouard Manet: Eternal Modern, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Conference, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Includes an honorary degree from the University to Nochlin.
  - Conference, History of Women in Barcelona, 1985-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Conference, Glasgow School of Art, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Conference, Multiplying the Visual in the Nineteenth Century: An Interdisciplinary Conference on Visual Culture at Columbia University, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Grant, Fulbright Program in Paris, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Grant, E. Harris Harbison Awards, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Fellowship, Guggenheim and American Council of Learned Societies, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Fellowship, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Membership, Century Association, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Panel, "Expressive Feminism" Talk with Lilibeth Cuenca Rasmussen at The Armory Show, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Panel, "Marxism and Feminism" at Whitney Museum of American Art, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Panel, "Site Matters: A Talk with LMCC's World Trade Center Resident Artists", 2005; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER054. (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Panel, Vassar in Paris, "The Idea of a Museum", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Photograph Requests, 1963-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Presenter, ArtTable Activities, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER103)
  - Presenter, New York Council for the Humanities Young Scholars of the Year Awards Dinner, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Program, Dahesh Museum Lecture Program, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Program, Margaret Cuninggim Lecture Program at Vanderbilt University, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Program, Visual Arts Summer in Morocco, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Proposal, Exhibition on 19th Century Women Artists in Paris, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Proposal, Film on Hannah Höch, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Symposium, Directions and Redirections: Impressionism Around 1880 at University of Michigan Museum of Art, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Symposium, Manet/Velázquez: The French Taste for Spanish Painting (1 of 2), 2003; Archival Resource Key; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Symposium, Manet/Velázquez: The French Taste for Spanish Painting (2 of 2), 2003; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Symposium on Matisse and Picasso, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 5 Sound cassettes (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Symposium, Old Favorites and the New Art History: Rethinking 18th and 19th Century French Painting in San Francisco, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Travel Arrangements, 1991-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Travel Ephemera, 1994-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Travel Expenses, 1993-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Teaching Files, 1953-2012; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 23-25, OV 36; 0.016 Gigabytes ER104-ER119
  The series contains files, including digital material, for courses taught by Nochlin at New York University Institute of Fine Arts and Vassar College. Other courses were taught at Hunter College, Columbia University, Stanford University, Williams College, and Yale University, where she was a visiting professor.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by course name or subject, then arranged chronologically within the folders.
  The series is divided into two subseries.
  6.1: Courses, 1953-2012
  6.2: Other Teaching Files, circa 1970-2012
  - Courses, 1953-2012; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    The subseries includes syllabi, bibliographies, lecture notes, faculty memos, reading material, and course descriptions. Folders may contain a mixture of material from multiple universities due to Nochlin's reuse of course material for the creation of new course material.
    - 2nd Empire Seminar, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 2nd Empire: Universal Exhibition of 1855, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 19th Century Criticism, 1981-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 19th Century French and English Criticism Colloquium, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 19th and 20th Century Art, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 19th and 20th Century French and English Criticism Colloquium, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - American Criticism, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Art Criticism from Diderot to Fry, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER104)
    - Art Criticism from Diderot to Fry, 1996-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Art and Dance Seminar, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Art and Dance in the 19th and 20th Centuries Seminar, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Art History Syllabus, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Art and Religion Seminar (1 of 2), 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Art and Religion Seminar (2 of 2), 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Art and Theater, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Bathers Seminar, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Beauty and Bathers Seminar, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Beauty Seminar, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER105)
    - The Big Picture, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - The Big Picture Seminar, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER106)
    - Body Seminar, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Body Seminar, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Body Seminar, 1991; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER107)
    - Body Representations Seminar, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - British Criticism Seminar, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Cézanne Seminar, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Cézanne Seminar, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER108)
    - Changing Representations of the Body (1 of 2), circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Changing Representations of the Body (2 of 2), circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Contemporary Women Artists Seminar, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 28)
      Also includes material related to two other courses: "Women Artists and Their Critics - Colloquium" and "Degas and his Critics."
    - Courbet and the Construction of Realism Seminar, 1991; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER109)
    - Courbet and Courbet Studies Colloquium, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Courbet Intro, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Courbet/Manet/Degas, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Courbet/Manet/Degas, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Courbet and Realism, circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Courbet and the Realist, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Courbet's Realism, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Courbet Reconsidered Seminar, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Courbet Seminars, 1992-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Courbet Seminars, 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Dance and Art, 2008-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - David to Courbet, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - David to Delacroix, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - David to Delacroix Revisited, 1986-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Degas and His Critics Seminar, 1971-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Degas and Impressionism, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Degas Seminar, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER110)
    - Delacroix and Romanticism, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Doing Criticism Colloquium, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Feminism and Art, 1983-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Feminist Studies, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Feminist Theory, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Feminist Theory, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Feminist Theory, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER111)
    - Feminist Theory Colloquium, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Gauguin and His Critics Seminar, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Gender and Art History Course, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Gender and Modernism, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Gender, Modernism and Visual Representation from Manet Through Cézanne, 1990-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Gender, Modernism and Visual Representation from Manet Through Cézanne, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 9 computer files (Folder ER112)
    - Gender, Modernism and Visual Representation from Manet Through Cézanne, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Gender and Visual Representation in the 19th and 20th Centuries, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Géricault Class, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Géricault Class, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Impressionism and Its Critics, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Impressionist Portrait Seminar, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Ingres Class, 1967-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Landscape and Portrait in the Mid-19th Century, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Make It Real! Seminar, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER113)
    - Manet Class, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Manet Class, Bibliography Computer Searches (1 of 2), 1973-circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Manet Class, Bibliography Computer Searches (2 of 2), 1973-circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Manet/Degas Seminar, 1987-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Manet and Degas, 1975-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Manet and Degas, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 13 computer files (Folder ER114)
    - Manet and Degas, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Manet and His Circle, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 37)